- You have a new project
and have decided agile is the best fit for it.
Now you have one more decision to make.
Which agile framework will work best for your project?
Remember, agile is a family of frameworks.
Each one of those frameworks lends itself
to specific situations.
The most common of the agile frameworks are scrum
extreme programming, XP for short, and kanban.
Remember, all agile frameworks require close interaction
between the customer and team.
They rely on collaboration.
They're geared toward responding to change when it arises.
So let's explore each of these to see
which might be best suited to your project.
Let's start with scrum.
Scrum is the most widely adopted of the frameworks.
Scrum is generally ideal for projects
where the customer representative
or product owner can be embedded in the team.
Scrum teams have fewer than 10 dedicated resources.
Due to its quick two to four-week cycles,
it does a great job at controlling scope creep
because within that time box it's hard
to add unneeded features.
It's also very good at delivering high-quality code
since all the work is tested and accepted
when the sprint ends.
At the same time, it does have some shortcomings.
Since scope is evolutionary in this framework,
without a strong product owner,
it's possible for the team to perform well,
but not deliver the most valuable features.
Further, you'll need an experienced scrum master
to keep the team on track.
Scrum is best suited to new development projects
or large enhancements to existing products.
It will simplify risk management
and address the potential scope creep for the project.
Next, let's talk about XP.
XP also requires a high degree
of involvement from your customer.
In this framework,
iterations tend to be shorter than with scrum,
coming in at a speedy one to three weeks.
The team structure is very light in XP
since the team members are only developers and the customer.
The benefit of the fast iteration in XP is
that the team can make it through areas
of high uncertainty or risk very quickly,
thus better enabling design.
On the downside, this requires a high level
of discipline from team members.
Also, there isn't a lot of time for documentation in XP.
Finally, you're better off
with the very experienced developers in this framework.
You'll need developers that are experienced
with their technology
and have excellent communication skills.
XP is best suited to new development projects
where there are high levels of uncertainty
and a need to learn quickly.
Finally, let's talk about kanban.
Kanban is best for small, dedicated teams of people.
Its focus is on eliminating waste
in the development process and increasing delivery rates.
Based on lean manufacturing principles,
the focus of this method is continuous delivery.
There are no sprints or iterations in kanban.
There's a backlog of work,
and the team's focus is working through the backlog
as quickly as possible.
Shortcomings for this method
include the potential for lack of documentation.
Also in this method, it's best to have a team of developers
that can complete work in any area of the product.
This will reduce waste times
and handoffs that can cause delays.
In most cases, kanban is best suited to projects
that are focused on existing product enhancement or support,
rather than new product build.
As you can tell, simply deciding between waterfall
and agile isn't enough.
You also need to choose which agile method is best.
When you keep these pros and cons in mind,
you'll be sure to make the right decision.